While people settling analysis and kind of welcome everyone welcome
...first session of...twenty fifteen is everyone excited to be here.
...enjoy the key notes
boy I tell you something there's nothing that I like more than coming on stage and follow hall
...demo moi.
...only...did everyone thing that they were all going to get
...samoa.
...that that's alex statement classic I tell you something though if all of you relating
...this would look a lot more interesting than it is moi.
Anytime you think...getting bored just imagine, you know,...the creative windows developers.
Anyway,...not off by a asking...question.
...how many of us developers like to write applications that nobody wants to...
You how many of us wish
...that absolute just sit in the uses apple there's an get new engagement from the users.
Now how many would change your answer if the user actually paid for the app and
lots of money moi.
Bunch agree...
The reality is I don't it's not surprising...are very few things
...more satisfying for developer the knowing that their product is being
engaging for the users...giving them value.
The more, you know, about the user the more you can give them value the more,
you know, and, understand how you can provide more...with so many applications competing for the
...attention on the phone it's a big challenge
...up and get your...shine through.
My name is...and I'm joined by tony...say hi
And, they're going to talk about how integrating with
...and...of health is going to allow your
...to be more differentiated and allow those applications to stand out.
Amended to slide that has been sneaked into my slider.
Everyone please...evaluation after the break out session this
...helpful for us and people who are actually organizing this to get more feedback thank you.
So, let's talk about quickly what's on the many for the next
sixty-minutes how many of us here have a mike sub-band.
...brilliant create so that remiss the first part is
...this now eval has still talk about...of
...just give you an overview of the cool technology because people are going to be watching this afterwards as well all the features that
...built then we're going to talk about how us developers can engage with
...and...of health.
In-between tony's going-to helping you some demos and at the end will have some time for question-and-answer.
So, what is mike subband?
...is and all the available device which was build with a few key principles in mind.
...designed to give you features that are going
...that...going to help you live healthier is also designed to help you
be more productive and keep you connected at a glance without having to reach free-form throughout the day.
These challenges coupled...the challenges of making something that is flexible and assist
...factor and is all the available result
in a product there is a combination of advanced technology and great engineering?
...sub-band has ten sensors...into very small form factor.
It also has a full-text display and it has...optimize
...battery life to give you over two days of normal use on a single charts.
Let's talk a little bit about the features of mike sub-band.
Microsoft when is far beyond your average run-of-the-mill step tracker what makes mike
subband unique is that it calculates your activity level your heartened metrics as well as
you sleep patents to give you a holistic picture of your health and fitness how does
it do that so it starts
...tracking is steps calories runs workouts and all the other exercises that you
...today and you go to sleep...tracks your sleep durations
...and things like resting heart rate to understand more about fiercely.
And, while...does all of that in the background with guided activities and custom activities
mike sub-band proactively taylor's your fitness of...to your needs
and goals and essentially acts like a fitness...on your wrist.
Productivity and connectivity are pillars that drive all the user engagement with the
microsoft.
What makes...subband unique
...this front is that gives you the right amount of information and it gives you
...the most?
So, things like incoming calls.
...social media updates nearby weather's keep you connected to things that you care about the most.
And, with...and calendar alerts, you know,
what to do and way to be even when you're on the move?
And, if you are user windows we bring...which is...personal system right on your...
All the data collected by
...of...goes up to the...of health service and it comes down informs of fridge
graphs and charts and trends that give you a detail view of your health.
Those charts and graphs combined with the on banned features that we just talked
about
we feel that...and...give you a holistic solution for health fitness and...
So, there was a bit about...of...of health.
And, while these features a great and...first part experiences that sell a lot...lots of
...and drive a lot of using in with the...event I wouldn't be standing here if that's all
everyday soon after we should...sub-band
...health recite looking in ways in which...bring third-party developers to, come
on, board engage with...microsoft so today we're going to talk about all the different reasons you can...the
...because system I'm going to start off by the first offering in this space.
Which is the...of ns...the purpose of the
mike subband instigate is to open of the mike sub-band to third-party developers to extend
enhanced experience of the applications with the...event?
So, essentially in a nutshell what the mike sub-band sdk does like all the
...it basically asked xtwo communication protocol between the phone and the
band and exposes...as a programming object so as developers all you need to
do is dropping a few namespaces create a
...client and usually google once you do have a...client.
There are a few main reason...you can interact with the...event you can stream data from the
...events answers you can also create your own tile and
...content into those tiles and you can also
...personalizing customize the...subband...going to talk today about all
of those things in more detail in a little bit but before that I want to make
...one big important point like all or most of the variables in
this category...subband does not provide a hosted application platform...really means is
it's and extensibility model so you always have to have an application running on the host
and then you can use the mike...as a rich input device as well as an auxiliary display.
So, let's talk about the first thing once you have a bank line
...for things that you can do let's not offered sensors so...
sub-band is the gay as we talk about michael...has ten sensors in a...form
...the...exposes access to those sensors encode.
So, you can using the...sub-band client...actually subscribe to the senses...as
...call them...subscribe to a...stream...to
...invoke all backs back into your code whenever there's new data available in those
things some of the data that you get back is going to be...sensor data and some of this is going to be curator
data that has been transformed onto the land to be more meaningful...
that's security data to get.
Let's take a look at some of the sensors on the...screens in
...so here's a table that talks about all the senses streams that
...semantic expo I'm not going to talk about all of them but the table axis shows the kind
...sensor that is behind that stream the...what would the data
that comes back is provided from that...and what is the frequency of getting that data so, for example,
if you look at the heart rate the value that comes back is the number of determinant which is the heart
...of the...and it also gives...reading quality which means...the
...is...on or whether...still in the process...the...to in the process of requiring that
...reading any provide that back and one
hertz which means once every second you get the data that some of the other senses like accelerometer and gyroscope give you
...more frequently and they also provide you a way to actually
change the frequency which wanted to get the data?
A...must be connected when your streaming where streaming or bluetooth of course so if the blue
...you know, your data...stop coming in some sense a require user
...authorization so if you're,
you know, of flashlight application that silently tries to get the users...for example,
the user actually has to authorize that app...go in and authorize...to get
...there are some there is some battery impact if you have longer in subscriptions because
we consuming bluetooth both on the on the phone site and...site but if you're running
sensors for many hours you have to be careful that they will be some kind of a backing.
So, I promise that tony's going to help us do some
demos so this is the first one of the series of demos is going to show us how using the
mike subband instigate you can create a band client and subscribe to a sensor.
Okay,
so, we'll start here in visual studio...get a new project
started we're going to build simple application here
...start off to streaming the
heart rate some so good simple example of streaming some sensor data.
We're going to draw the demos today in visual studio run this
on windows phone we've got here we do release...sdk for all
of the major platform so if you're android or ios developer you'd be using
our native sdk for your platform and using your favorite development environment.
So, we're going to start an as I do the demo today just because we've got a lot of
ground cover going to be dragging and some code snippet some not going to try to do a lot of typing on-the-fly
just to help keep things moving here so we'll be working with
a phone apps so let's make that are startup project and in the first thing I'll do is
go grab the new get package for our sdk and we'll get that installed here.
And, we'll just get the.
Couple of dialogues here there we go.
Ok.
Now let's.
Go drop...just a little bit of simple ui here.
So, I'm just going to put a few controls on...
Simple grid here.
Okay, so, I've got a text field here...produce can put some
status matches messages so we can see what's going on in the app got a couple of buttons
...we used to start and stop the streaming of the heart rate data and then I've got another text
block down here we'll put the data as we get back from the band
ok so that's our simple ui let's go over the code here.
And, first I'm going to
droppings musing statements so you saw the namespaces
...was mentioning earlier so we've got the...tiles tell pages...come to some
...somewhere that later and, then the other really key thing is that
band clients I'm going to make a private member here...this class and the
...client is going to be essentially rr portal into the functionality the
band and we'll see how we get that set up here so I'm going to do all of the...
most of the logic here is just going to go right into our on navigated to method.
I'm just going to remove those comments and drag and some code here.
And, the first thing that we want to do is just identify the bands that we've got
paired so we're going to numerator bans and select one to talk to.
One thing I'll just mention here we're going to do all the initialization here on the
first load of this page so if we come into here with a navigation...other
the new we're just going to bail-out so we're just focusing on that on that one navigation
mode the other thing I need to do here...make this a...
Ok, so, now you can see here we're going to the client managerwe're getting that singleton
instance and then we're just going to say get the
...and do this asynchronous...so that's going to enumerate all of pared...normally
you would only have one band paired with your device but the sdk actually supports any number of
...you might want to have paired so ...demo purposes we're just going to get the first one
...say first or default here and then for some reason we didn't recognize a
banner didn't find one paired...just set the status and bail-out?
Okay, so, the next thing we're going to do is actually make that connection to the
band so I'm going to set the status message before and after so we can see what's
going on here and then the key is that we're going to go back to that
instance the singleton instance on the
...client manager and just say connect and we're going to actually give it the
...we identified previously so now we've got our
band connection and the next thing that we want to do is get set up to receive that
heart rate information and one of the things I'll show you here is how we deal
with that authorization stepped...was talking about some...dragon a snippet of code and what
will look at is how we check to see if we already have authorization and if not how we
going to ask the user to get their permission to receive the heart rate data?
...in here.
The sdk remembers...you
vast user once for their permission will actually remember that so you don't have to ask the
user every time so the first thing that we're going to do.
I must be...into the wrong place.
So, the first thing we're going to do is go to the sensor manager under
...band clients...reason that...client...band are going to go to the heart rate
...specifically and then we're going to check the current consent setting
ok so I'll just switch on that so if the
users previously declined or granted permission then we have our answer and,
...dab if this is the first-time here...
We're actually going to go into the sensor manager again heart rate and now we're going
to request consent so as we execute the app here in a moment you'll see this is going to pop-up
stimuli or we ask for the consent in the user can either approve or
disapprove that request.
Ok, so, once we get out of that switch statement we've got our answer and if the user
has given us consent.
Then we want to go set-up and event handler to respond to that information as a starts
to come in so again we go back to the sensor manager the heart rate sensor and...going to set
up or of handler for this reading...and it's going to be and asynchronous
handler and all we're going to do here is just go back to the main thread and set
that text field we looked at where we wanted to show the heart rate information and we're just going to
...that format using both the quality and
heart rate number so we'll see whether we're still acquiring
...or whether we've actually gotten locked on to the users heart rate and then we'll see what the value...
And, then just to for completeness here if we didn't get consent and we'll just note that in the status
field.
The only thing...here to do or put in some simple handlers for
thosefor those buttons so we had the start and stop buttons there on the screen we
saw so when we start reading the heart rate...we do is go back to the heart rate
sensor and just say start reading a...return we can say stop.
that's it we're ready to start the app up so I'll go select the
device move fire that up so that's going to build.
And, deploy and we'll see this come up over here on our phone
in just a moment what other showing you the...screen here because we're not doing anything with the
...yet so we won't see anything happening over here.
So, the app is coming up and you see it's connecting.
Connected and now we go right into this authorization
...that up so I'll.
Do that and now we're ready to start reading my heart rate
we'll see how stressed out I am during the demo here ...pretty good
seventy five that's not bad and stan things are under control?
if I wait a few seconds we should see that go from acquiring to locked.
Improves the confidence that it has okay...are locked
...ok, it's going up a little bit still...figured but my benchmark today
...if I if I can get to this point under a hundred that's probably pretty good okay.
Okay, so, that's part one and I'll turn it back over to...to tell you somewhere.
So, that was about sensors as you saw that getting...data from
...events sensors does not allow you or does not require you to create anything on the
...event you can user application on the phone and it can just get stream data from the
sensors and you can use that data...it...you want but if you want to use the...of
...display as an observer display you would want to create tiles on your
...you want to once...and content into those tiles so the mike sub-band as
...you interact create interactive tiles on the microsoft so
let's quickly talk about how to do that once you have a...client and you're ready and you connectivity like
...your application can then go ahead and create one
or more tiles so all you need to do in order to create a tile is you need to have
and the dollywood and specify a couple of icons...uses to show up on the
...event and that's it additionally if you want your app can actually have or your tile can have up to
eight additional icons those icons will be used in pages so
what are these pages when the user taps
...your tile it goes into the content inside of that
tile that content is represented to what we call pages italian have up to
eight pages each one of these page has a view port of two forty five hundred six pixels
it's vertically scrollable seo content can be cold inside of a single page vertically
the user slice horizontally the user basically navigate between different pages so
you can operate pages these pages how do you create these pages these pages can be created
...is one of the ways to create them to genetic messaging notifications
the other way is to create than using custom layouts so we'll talk about both of those innovate?
Once you have event landing...connected to event client you can send notifications to
microsoft that there are three major types of notifications the first one
are messages that we just talked about in the previous slide...title in
a body style notification so you basically take a bank language...into your tyler chose up the
title the body the body scrollable vertically so that's a page
...a very simple layout you can have up to eight messages sent there in the first in first out
q when you send the ninth message the first one that...is just going to
...so that...you can have a continuous stream of communication with the band
from your applications that's one form of notifications sometimes you want
to notifications which do not require you to
...or persist inside of a tile those
...popper dialogues when you send a dialogue it shows up onto the mike subband
...dismisses the dialogue the dialogue goes away and the
uses basically never sees that again so that's just to inform the user of something that...immediately
happen once it's gone it's gone forever sometimes it's even useful...notification without any
ui so those are vibration alerts that you can use the sd allows you to send a
predefined set of vibration types to inform the user of some
...feedback that you want to get them or some activity or if you want to just get their attention without any us.
So, right on the right inside agency some example of
how this content shows up the other way to create pages inside of your tiles is to custom layouts
so with messages all you get is a title in a body and the body has up to one sixty characters and
...scrolls and that's it but if you want fine-grain control over the content shows up and what
if you want to icons and images and buttons you want to use a custom layouts?
So, when you d create a...event tile you can register up to five layouts each one of these
layouts is can is...a tree it's an object model where you have container elements within those
contain elements who can have other container elements or you could have content primitive elements that contain
content at the end of all of this the container elements do not show up on the
on the...the content element show up the content elements that you have?
Yeah, so, the table right here shows you the container elements in the primitive elements
container elements you can have low...scrolls
...of three panels and the content elements could be text could be buttons...be bar codes it could be icons.
All of these elements support positioning formatting and styling so...can actually
...position each one of these elements on the page exactly where...you want them to.
Here's a couple of examples on the right-hand side bottom these are built in the
...use for some of the content the visual inside...like submit.
Once you have a layout then you can use that layout to create a page...that page over the
...so...actually has a addressing schema
...every tile actually has its good every page inside...tile has its own
good and within the page every single element has its own element id
so essentially when you have a tile do it you can create a page using a given layout and by once you
have a layout you can specify the elements each one of the elements in the value of...the content that you want to
...for those elements and that's how you create a page so-if the layout had three are
...lines...icon all...to do is say okay I'm going to use this layout and then you specify your
three text lines whatever lines want to show up you specify the index of the
icon which is one of the nine or ten index that all the icons that you've created before and
then you have a page once you have a page you add a page to your tile by specifying a page
...if a page good already exist inside of your tile
...essentially updating the contents of that page automate
inline so if I centipede before but I now want to update that page I will create a
new page with the same...and send that page over it will update the contents
of that page if a good as a new one that means another page will get added to your dial
again you can have operate pages once you send the...
pages going to push the page the first very first page out of the...so you only have eight pages.
When you have pages you can put like I said you can put buttons on these pages so you would want to
know end-users interacting with those...so you've
...deceive events back using the sd from these pages the
ethically allows you to actually...three different major kinds of events that you can
subscribe to these are pretty self-explanatory by the...the user open your tile you get a
...that says the use...enter your tile the user...your tile you'll get a notification
...the approaching the user has left...once...inside of your tile and
he presses any of the buttons the code on your code will get events the event
...button pressed with the id of the element idea of the
button was pressed inside of a particular page so you'll know exactly which button expressed?
Couple of things to remember here events...handle slightly differently
per platform and that's kind of the limitation...you have to work with when you're working across
platforms so on android, for example, we use broadcast intense.
What that means is your app can be...it's not running because the app is a registered intent and
...service can actually cause ...that...and get your core to execute on ios we
use bluetooth low-energy custom characteristic essentially that gives us a
little more flexibility when the app is not in the foreground even if it
is a background as long as the app has an active connection to the band you can actually...this the called
...on windows...direct communications which means the app
called has to be actively running in order to received the call that say the...is not running and,
some activities happen on the band right now there is no way for us to...called back...the
...to the...however with windows tenuous windows platform we have this thing called
...services those absences will allow non running applications just
like on android to be able to invoked from the...event?
So, let's quickly handover back to tony...going to show us how using the
...as...you can create interactive...on the...open.
Okay, so,
we're going to go back to the same map and we'll just pick up where we left off and we're going to do now
is create a custom tile and within our tile we're going to create one-page
with custom layout and on that page were going to put to buttons
...afloat panel with the horizontal orientation and then we'll just
put one-button another button and...put and awfully able and one
...on label...the other room and then we'll see how we can get events back from those.
So, I'm going to dragon
helper method here that's going to do most of the work for us.
Okay,
and, there's a lot of code here a little more code than we've looked at so far but I'll walk through this whole thing.
First thing to notice that this code is designed to work whether it's the first
...subsequent times through so you'll see you see that pop-up in
the logic here the first thing we do is
establish the goods for the tile and the page the next thing we
want to do is go to tile manager and get our current set of tiles
now this is filtered by app so this is not looking at all the custom tiles that have been added this
is just the ones that I've added myself so we could have added multiple tiles in this demo
...only adding one so what I want to do here is just see have we already out
of the tile to this to the spanned or not okay so again we're going to call first
...default if we get null back in the tile that means we have no tile yet so we're going
to go construct the tile and then send it to the band so walk through that here.
So, the first thing we're going to do is make a
...panel that we can put those buttons inside.
Case or constructing that we give
...element id zero we're setting the rectangle to use a
...the full usable area on the tile
are orientations horizontal and we want to center that
ok so now we can go start but some elements within that within that
flow panel so we'll go to our elements collection animal at
a text button and we'll give it a new element id one
...sort of width here and we're going to set what color we want to be when that
...and you can see one thing here we've got an extension method here on
the color object so that we can convert that to up suitable object for use with the band.
So, we'll skip down here you see we're adding a second button
given a new element id but, basically the same thing going on there.
So, now we're going to make
are page layout and then we're going to set as the...object on the layout that's just going to
be that flow panel that we made up above so now we've got our layout let's go make
our tile...self-serving to...tile...give it our tile guid.
And, the first thing we want to do is given a name so the
name is important because when the user goes to the microsoft health
...and they go into the manic tiles section on there what you'll see
...at the bottom after all of the first party
tiles you'll see a list of third-party tiles and this is how your tile will be identified in
that list k and then we're going to set up to icons that we want to use for that.
...so, now we've got our tile object it slowly made it's got it's layout we've added the
layout here and now we can go to the tile manager and just say
add tile can that's what's really,
really doing the work to set that up.
Now so that was all work that we wanted to the very first-time when we didn't have that tile
there yet it all on every time that we run through this code we want to go
...that page and provide the page its content so you notice
in the layout we didn't have anything about the labels on those buttons so this is where
that comes out so we're going to go to tell manager again...set pages a
...we've got our tile good now we're going to make a new page data object
and we say here's the good this says which page we're talking about
zero says I want to use the first layout we only have one layout so,
we're using that layout that's just the index and, now we want to pass a couple of objects
that provide the content for the elements on there...so this is where we get to
...labels so that's all the work that we need to do to create
that tile now let's go back up into our on navigated to method and let's just
flush that out with some code to first.
Creator initialize that tile so that's the code that we just looked at now we're going to set up
or event handlers.
So, we've got...opened
...anti button pressed events so for each one of those were just going
...message into that status area that we were using before and,
for the for the button event we're also going to reach into our
...and get the element id so we can see which button
...okay and then there's just one more thing we need to
do go add the icons.
Here so I'll just go grab those.
And, those to our project.
Ready to build that.
Now you notice is the application comes up this
time we won't have to ask the user for the heart rate permission because we did
that already so we'll see it skipping that step this time.
we get we get this dialog so we always asks user permission to add a tile
...the icon is provided here so they can get a sense for what application is asking
to do this and, you see the name of the tile...their...give permission and you see on the
...sinking so we're pushing the p icons for the tile the
layouts all that information is
coming down here if I scroll to the far-right...smiley face that's my tile
icon and as I open this up we'll see an open event here and
...also see our custom content so we've got our on off button
...we saw the tile open event and as I press...see the button,
button events coming in?
And, then we'll see the tile closed.
So, now you can see, you know, we've kind of got all the tools we need in our toolbox now to start
making some really really more compelling scenarios with the band.
you know, as I was finishing up this demo...work, you know, a couple of weeks ago
...was kinda cool, you know, we've showed you how to put all this together but, you know,
it's a little dry, you know, it's, you know, it's text on a display here
we're just pressing some buttons and I thought it would be fun to do something a little more interesting with us so I
email some folks and the io t space and said hey, you know,
what would be a good the could gadget we could maybe hook up to this and do something with
and I learned about some of the work that we were doing with the folks from instilling on so there's
an all join talk going on right now unfortunately where the scandal
audience down folks are but, what I learned is that with their new hub this
is their new home automation too they have a cloud api the instantiate api
turns out that's really easy-to-use so in just a couple of hours with some sample code that the institute
...me what I did was take
that sample app and just extend a little bit so wrote a little client wrapper
for their api I took the layout that we just looked at and I just
added a text field on the top of it and then I added some code to go reach
out to my home automation network and I've got to instantiates which
modules here onstage small fire up this app?
now we're going to authenticate within scion so I've got the credentials here for the networks that I set
up and we're connects the band I'll go login to instill...
...see a found...found both my switches it knows the name so
that's actually enumerating over this devices that we got back we've got the name and we
pushed those device names down to tiles or
...pages behind my tile here so you can see I've got my living room
light in my bedroom light so that was all content that came dynamically through,
through calling in stan.
So,...turn assign there's, there's one...
And, should there's the other one so...success?
One thing tony didn't talk about was his life almost left him because he was standing on thanks in his bedroom
on asf from is office throughout the day...great creature a little bit, yeah, okay,
so, that was creating tiles and creating buttons and getting interactive stuff back from the
likes event couple of things that we didn't talk about today in the interests of time a while talking
about the educators...event...the also allows you to personalizing
...sub-band...of things that we do allow you to customize our the
...and the team color for the...scheme.
Of what is the me tile the media is a main tile that shows up when you go into the into the
...of...the use of...on the...of nsf...that you see so them using the...can actually
get that metallic and also...do anything you like...lot of you probably are already using apps that
actually doing this another thing is my some as six different colors that comprise microsoft
ranting using the as you can actually change that team and you can change the look and feel of the
...the same theme is useful your application tiles so-if you want-to change the team of your particular
tile and the different on the maintain you can use the same the same...class to do that.
So, just to recap ...of an as you saw today that we can use
...to get to access sensors you can use the...of as you to create your own tiles and send data in get
events back from those and...we talked about how you can...might subband by using the
...my semantic is currently available on developer
...sub-band dot com it's available on windows android and ios it's in a preview
where we're excited to bring it to you in a full released very soon.
If you're and, if you're not...developer...for all different platforms and use
said use examine be has eminent bindings for all of this negate the
functionality have a portals last library that you can use and you can just target one
...of api as and generate apps for all three platform.
So, that was all about...event as began how you can write applications that can communicate with the
...or what if you one of those developers who does not like to...apps
...doesn't want to write apps for the mobile platforms at all but if you have a service or
what if you have someone who has content on the post on the internet and you want to bring that content on to the
mikes on that?
It really necessary to actually have an application running on the on
a phone in the beginning I said you have to have an application running while that is
...I never said that it has to be an application that you have to write so today
...very excited to talk about and give you an early look into this thing that we
working on which is what we call web-based mike subband...
What essentially these are tiles that exist on you might...the powered by the
The way we do it is the...
Is always accompanied by myself...that myself how that is present and all the platform that you're running a
...event or...of bandwidth my somehow that allows my
subband to be connected to the internet so we thought why not use the our of the
...of health and use internet connectivity that provided by the...of held app and allow the
...sub-band to get content from the internet I thought about a
very different many different ways in which you could, you know,
talk about this but reality is the easiest way I could think
of was imagine you have favorites on your web page or you
have analysis feed that you really like to go and you want to see new content on it every day so this is
...way of enabling mike sub-band to actually reach out and get content from the internet
so what you have to do is you all you have to specify is the source of the content and
you'd have to specify the...you...that condom to show up on the...event and let the microsoft help app
connect the dots and do the rest for you so essentially it really brings what I'd like to
...tiny browser on the mike subband before even freaks out
is not project many spartan or anything like that this is just decorative
way of bringing content from the internet without having to write any logic on any of the platforms?
So, why you would want to do this?
It lowers the value twenty of using...of n and leverage our of mike
sub-band dramatically you don't have to write any apps you don't have to know...code you don't have
...object...java csharp all you need to do is just understand some markup languages and you should be
good to go another way to simple in portable you have your content already in the on the internet
...just bringing into a new surface so that's
very powerful and again this is one more way of you reaching your users
...them in into content that you create.
Who would be interesting into this developers already have content and they want to light up that content
...the...this is going to be powerful tools for them and also into used who liked
...know exactly what content they want maybe they don't own that content but they still want to see that content on the
...event...going...tools that is going to be very powerful for them quickly let me talk about what the
...experience looks like so as a reptile author?
The first thing you do is you would author your tile what does that authoring mean
...means all you have to specify is where is this data source that you're interested in
what are the layouts that...interested in...how do you want...data source to
show up in that layout and that's what we call data mining so you ever data that's coming from the internet you have a
layout that you've created and you want that layouts to somehow show that content
you basically buying some of the parts that content using that layout...on the my sub-band once you've author
dilution publisher...hosted you can storage however you wanted.
You can...people you can use a social media e-mail or just send urls to share
...this content and then let the microsoft
...app do the rest of the work for you and by the rest of the work I mean...of...
scale of installing it also textile managing and make sure the data coming in into your tiles
all this fresh and is refresh...
So, what is this reptile...that I keep mentioning it's basically a zip file format
that we're exploring it has a
couple mandatory things that you have to have a couple of optional things that you can add...do things are
the manifest file this is the file that talks about everything that you need to create a tile on the
...events so describes your tile it also tells you where the data source for that
...coming from it also contains a data bindings for the payload so, you know,
this is the data want to show and this is how I want to show it couple of...another thing that you want is you want
image files because you creating a title mikes...then it has to like on those that icons for the images?
If you want finer-grained controls often the
...have custom layouts so you can have more granular control of the how
the content shows up you could use some of the built-in layout slider title embody or
some basically out-of-shape or you can have your own custom layout in the future you can imagine you can
have javascript files which can use be used to do they meant handling for you and the
...has...actually host tacked on your behalf and basically do all the work for you.
...a concept there is much more easily understood...you see code since this is the
...audience I'm going to start talking lesson that...little more of the demo.
So, when we started thinking about this idea a lot of our thinking was kind of spurred on by some
conversations we're having with...handsome and who you saw earlier today...the keynote doing some
measure demos and I think he's here in the talkers as well and
he had a really compelling, compelling scenario that we've kind of used to drive our thinking on this
scott is diabetic and he wears a blood glucose monitor that is
monitoring his blood glucose levels twenty four seven now that monitors connected to
a device or phone I think that the pushes that up to asher so
this is scott's live blood glucose data and
scott had a band for a while when...we first talked...a few months ago and he said
what he would really love is to be able to get the same information
right on his band and have it be kind of constantly refreshed and current
...pulling apart phone out-of-pocket and going to look at that he's just got
...really convenient way right there on his wrist so we took that idea
and we've kind of built...demo around that?
So, what I'll do is go look at a simple web tile that will do
that for us so this is a directory where we're building the tiles
organism this up in a moment but we've got
an icons directory hereyou see we've got a couple of a blood droplet like
icons and we've got our manifest so let's go look at the manifest?
And, I'll go up to the top here.
And, you can see there's some, you know, kind of boiler plate information that you'd expect to see here we've got
a manifest version we've got a name for the tile longer description that we might want to
shown in gallery if we were going to collect a bunch of tiles together and show them to
userssome version information author
and contact information and then we've got pointers to those icon so we've got an app icon
...we might use on the phone or desktop to give us a nice rich representation
of our tile and, then we've got, you know, the actual forty-six my forty-six
tile that we want to use on the band itself.
Okay,
now the next thing that we have here is...section where we talk about resources sosa
...saying this is where we talk about what we're going to reach out to the web
...information from and you can see it's an array of objects so we could actually
have multiple resources that were drawing from in this case we have one and
we're going to do is go up to scots measure site he's got a site
there that we can just do a get on and what we'll get back as a
...payload with the information about his current
...glucose status another style?
Member here is interesting we're thinking about a number of different
scenarios here solely was talking about...assessed speeds, for example, so,
you might want to have a web tile where you're actually looking for
new feed items to come in and just pulling off those new feed items in this case in
scott's case what we have is a single static payload that's
going to be changing I mean static in its format but the contents of that are going
to be changing so we're calling that a simple style but,
we envision a number of different styles to make it really, really easy to deal with
common internet content scenarios.
So, the next thing we want to do is reach
in just pluck out the fields of that of that data that we're interested in so what we're
going to do is to set up a binding from a name that we can use internally here
and the manifest to an actual path into the content so here we're just, you know,
creating a json style expression there's a top-level object pcs
there's an array and then...tv field is what's going to give us the current,
current reading out of their
similar similarly for the other fields here there's a time stamp that will tell us, you know, when
was...this reading collected so, this gives us...that we need to popular tile?
So, now the second half of that is how do we do we actually
get that content down on to the page.
we've got the pages section here and again you can see...an array of objects we get a multiple pages so we
could be taken content from the web and then spreading that across as many pages as we
like and this case we've got one page and we're going to use a built-in layout so we've got
a built-in layout that are baptist understands natively and will document
...set of these on this case we're going-to do is put, you know,
the thing that's got cares about most is what is my current blood glucose levels so
we'll make that nice and big on the left side of the tile and then we'll show some of
this other information in smaller text fields to the right so we know the element idea of this is
one and then mobile do a set the value just by using this string
substitution syntax we've got here so double curly says I want to go back to
that named current that I bound earlier and just insert that here?
...do the same thing for the direction which gives us a general trend indication
and we've got the delta and now we're going to take, you know, the delta information that we got back from the
web but also had some units of measurement here and then finally for the updated
this is a little interesting so we've got some static text here
...referring back to the time stamp but then we've got
a helper here that says I want to take that unique style time stamp...it to
our human friendly short time format so we'll have some set of these
two again help you deal with really common scenarios for data transform transformations
that you might want to do.
So, that's it it's really you can think of it is kind of a transducer
between content on the web and the format that I want to see it in on my band.
So,I'll.
Just sit these up.
And, then.
I'll talk a little bit about this extension so...the
extension to web tiles we have to mechanisms in the microsoft health up that help
...this installation process of these web tiles really seamless so
we're registering for the web tile file suffix we also are registering
for a customer
all scheme so you'll be able to create pages that maybe have a little band
icon and, you know, you can make it easy for your users to go grab the content that
you're providing to them put it on their band just by just by using a
customer all scheme their refers to your ...web tile.
So, what I'm going to do is I've made a
one drive folder where I'm working on authoring these things and testing so I'm just going
to copy this over to a short-cut here I've got for that?
For that one drive folder.
Ok, so, now...move over to the phone.
And, I've got that same folder pinned to my
start screen here small open that up.
...there's my web tile and because we registered for that file
suffix I can just open that.
And, we launch right into microsoft health and it's going to go read the manifests
now get the information from map and we'll see we'll get that same kind of.
...were going to well.
...start.
Yeah, my harvard's I'm sure my harvard's...good thing we don't have the showing...that's.
It's talking to the band.
Okay,...in here I'll show you there's the third-party...we
...before so the...demos the app that we added you can see the nc on
demo so let's come back out of here let's try one more time.
Serially this worked.
Mirror minutes ago maybe have...time.
Which...
...that upon more time.
...doing that,
yeah, go ahead as if it's not obvious this is a technology that...are just working on right
now...love to get your feedback on this there is there's a
lot of creativity that we get from
people's feedback from developers feedback this is one of those places that you can actually have your voices
...so, please I'm going to talk about the ways in which you can contact us but,
feel free after the after the session or even after will be in the windows inside
...you can talk to us there or in the explodes on or afterwards...an email to
us and...try to incorporate your feedback into this maybe one of the way
...going to be make installation work better.
If you have any ideas we could go ahead and start taking questions if you want to keep trying to get the skunk.
Yeah, that's good and...questions...that.
All right so trust me that...
works maybe tony's going to fix it...the time we have you will be able to see a
...which is getting content life content from the internet from the source that's...has it's
a powerful tool it doesn't require you to do any of the application of an need to
submit to any store any at anything like that just quickly brings powerful content on to the...about.
So, we looked at
...event sdk which directly interfaces...then we talked about how you can use
...of health the applications to...some of the content on
...mikes and then we also have this thing in the cloud recall...health service.
So, a lot of people ask about what about that thing when we launched the...of
...the...key partnership with some third-partyservices like run
keeper map my fitness and more recently style imap...
Want to be more open most of these partnerships...done the deep collaboration between microsoft and these third parties
...exchange data to the service called...
...want to be more open and...by developers and...users to actually...the data collected by
...of health with other...services this way,
you know, people who already have existing relationship third-party services they can actually
integrate all of the data and make sure that it shows up in one place...it shows up...and they wanted
...so we're very excited and we're working on building microsoft...aps
are going to allow third-party developers to do that what will these third these api
going to be open...based on...platforms is going to
be restful api is that are allowed third-party developers to enhance the experience of
their absence services...rich fitness content coming from microsoft helped so this
will allow those application services to craig the fitness of their users more comprehensive
lee additionally if you have a device that collect sensor datayou'll
...have an opportunity to take that data and send it over an integrated all the
cool data that's collected...helped once we have that ecosystem in place if
...writing and app and service and you're in your targeting...you will not only appealed to the uses a
...of health but you would also...to all of the users of all the partners that are
...of microsoft so quickly take a look at some of the...as...you're going to expose things like user
profile information once you...you will know the basic user profile information of the...of
...users.
You will get some historical sensor data so with sdk you can get
real-time sensor data with the healthy as you can actually get...time
...historical sense of data that you will also be able to get summaries hourly weekly and daily
...or monthly summaries...various things like
steps distance galleries heart rate etc.
In addition all the activities that...do run bike
workout guide guided workouts you will be able to get access to those and now you can use the
data to enrich the experience of your applications...all of the fitness data is coming from microsoft
health additional thing would be sleep tracking you will get to know what the sleep patterns are for those
users once the choose to share the data redo and also if they have
any other connected devices you will also be able to do get to know about those devices.
So, let me just put...summary slide.
So, we talked about the how you can extend the experience of your...using the
...sdk...we talked about how you can bring a web content to life than my on
...using the...of held app and last in the not least
...we talked about how you can enrich your apps and services data for microsoft...very
...bring all of these things to ua soon and we are really,
really hopeful that you have some feedback and get us to make this more but even
...in the future here's some of the resources you can get the as
...developer the...dot com I talked about that.
It has some great samples has some good documentation shun you can go in develop starting right
...you...some and myself...websites where you can get to know more about the products
we have a conversation log polynomial conversations this...should go to get all the
...news and announcements about...of health and last I promise you I'll give you an alias
...you can contact us so health...and microsoft-dot-com that's if you have...
questions any feedback anything you want to tell us that's the areas that you wantto go out.
Another slide that has been sneaked in please...I don't know-how to how it's done I'm
...you guys have a more information on that but leisure feedback is valuable it's going to you know,
make sure that I get a chance to talk to-you next...if you guys like me.
Thank you so much for being here I know this is the first session you all came over I
really appreciate that thank you so much andwe will take some questions unless.
Now all right we'll take some questions.
Thank you thank you please come to the microphone.
Yeah, so.
So, we are very aware of the fact that myself has different offerings so if you really dig in their these
...different things we do have a
...on converging together and coming up with something that is one holistic...
...dance.
So, I there is no theoretical limit I don't know-how the phone's behaves if you have
multiplayer I think you would hit whatever bluetooth limits you'd run into on...that I don't think the
...has any I think...itself
...there might be a certain number of...that the phone can store once you
...that...limit and you...be able to update any other bags.
The question is what is...unicode support for the
and vendors sport unicode but it doesn't support chinese japanese or
the languages that's something that we are looking into the enabling.
Well,...depend on the phone very does
...it's a matter of localizing all of the apps and, you know,
that's definitely something we are looking into this.
I don't know let's I'm sorry.
You if you can run...the background...techniques and fix to make that happen
you're you don't have to be in the...down in those cases so like if you're if
you're music application, for example, you can run as a music backgrounds
...task and that point you are actually connected all but if you're if you're not
...one is very aggressive and suspending apps and...we can't do anything about that.
There is no simulator right now...gotten that feedback many...people say you have like
a skin temperature sense...how to aac simulate different temperatures when looking into enabling something like that
and yes but right now there is...
So, the question is how...the calories computed of is
...a sensor is something that...so the calories are basically calculated on the from
...us using your height...a gender and,
also the your heart rate all throughout the day so that's something that's impropriety algorithm that we have on the from
...that doesn't there's no sense and that tells us...calories.
So, again, that's a program algorithm that we worked onand, it's not something there is no
...that tells us if you're...asleep again it's a it's a matter how much
of moving what is your if your...going all the way down...artery that telly theaterI can
...information our algorithms team would love to...some that information.
The ethically works across all applicant all the platforms so you
see on windows yes so if you're on windows
you will have to be a runtime application to be...use that.
Currently the...not work on those unless you have some...of rapping
...unmanaged to manage interface.
Tony...I don't I don't know of any plants the...right now.
Thanks for over time.